My name is Aoba Kurage.
我是蒼葉海月
I'm about to enter high school
即將升上高中
and become a remarkable adult woman.
成為一個出色的成年女性
But I still want to develop myself.
但是 我還想要繼續成長
This little guy is Nyagosuke.
這個小傢伙叫喵仔
Keeping a diary is a sign of adulthood.
寫日記就是成年的證明
It's the first step
這是為了有所成長
to reflect on oneself for growth.
而重新審視自己的第一步
Sis Kiki once said,
嬉嬉姐曾經這樣說過
the most important thing recently
要說最近發生的最重要的事情
is that Akagami came to our temple.
果然還是赤神哥哥 來到我們寺廟的這件事吧
I'm so dizzy…
我頭好暈…
Are you okay?
妳沒事吧
He was very gentle to me.
他當時對我十分溫柔
It must be because
這肯定是因為
he treated me like an adult woman.
他將我當成了成年女性來對待
I'm an adult!
我是大人了
Finished…
我寫完了…
I can take another step forward now.
這樣我就能更上一層了
Speaking of which,
話說回來
Akagami really is an incredible person.
赤神哥哥還真是個不可思議的人
Since he came,
他來了以後
our family has gradually changed
我們家也逐漸出現了變化
…in a good direction.
而且…還是朝著好的方向發展
As long as he is here,
只要有赤神哥哥在
I don't have to worry about what to write in my diary anymore.
我也不用煩惱日記裡該寫什麼了
Kurage, dinner is ready.
海月 飯做好囉
Coming.
好
WORLDLY DESIRES
(世俗雜念)
A bath feels so good.
(第六話 Let's 既定事實) 泡澡泡得好舒服呀
Now the girls' meeting starts.
現在開始女生會議
The atmosphere is so solemn.
這個氣氛好凝重
Every time after I take a bath,
我每次洗完澡
I weigh myself.
都會量一下體重
I found that the scale is cursed.
但是我發現體重計被詛咒了
Yes, the manifestation of the curse is,
是的 詛咒的表現形式就是
the number shown is much higher than expected.
顯示出來的數字要比預想的高很多
-So you just gained weight. -And what's amazing is,
-那不就是妳變胖… -而且奇妙的是
this only started happening after Akagami came.
這個現像是從赤神來了以後 才開始出現的
DELICIOUS MEAL
(美味的餐點)
ONE MORE BOWL
(再來一碗)
-I'll have one more. -Me too.
-再來一碗 -我也是
I bet some of you here have also been hit by the same curse.
在座的各位 應該也有人中了同一個詛咒吧
This is indeed a curse, Sis Yuzuki.
這確實是詛咒呢 結月姐
It's a curse.
是詛咒
I'm glad you understand.
我很高興你們能理解
So let's discuss how to lift the curse.
那麼 我們來探討一下 解除詛咒的對策吧
-I know! -Please say it, Mia.
-我知道 -米亞 請說
How about buying a new scale?
我們要不要買一個新的體重計呢
Mia, this is a serious discussion.
米亞 我們可是很認真地 在討論這個話題
This is no time for jokes.
玩笑還請適可而止
I'm sorry.
對不起
Kagura.
神樂
Let's continue our discussion about losing weight…
那我們就繼續探討減肥…
No, about breaking the curse.
不是 探討解除詛咒的方法吧
-I know! -Please speak, Mia.
-我知道 -米亞 請說
How about controlling your sugar intake?
控制一下攝取的糖分怎麼樣呢
A CHANCE FOR REDEMPTION
(挽回名譽！)
I heard that altering your diet to primarily vegetables and meat
我聽說將飲食結構 轉變為以蔬菜和肉類為主的話
can help you lose weight quickly.
很快就能瘦下來
We're broke…
我們沒錢…
We can't afford meat…
我們沒錢買肉啊…
And the price of vegetables has gone up recently…
而且蔬菜最近也漲價了…
I'm truly sorry.
非常抱歉
-I know. -Please speak, Tsukuyo.
-我知道 -月夜 請說
Maybe some exercise?
我們果然還是得靠運動吧
It has come to this after all.
果然也只能這樣了呢
I want to try Pilates.
我想嘗試一下普拉提
I see.
我知道了
It's hard to stick with it alone.
一個人很難堅持下去
But if we all work together, it shouldn't be a problem.
但是大家一起努力應該就沒問題了
We'll start tomorrow morning.
那麼 我們就從明天早上開始運動吧
It's actually quite challenging.
這個還挺難做的呢
That's how you work your inner muscles.
但是 我聽說就是這樣 所以才能鍛煉到深層肌肉呢
ENDURING PILATES Enduring… Pilates.
(苦行 普拉提) 苦行…普拉提
This is… exercise for adults…
這個就是…成年人的運動…
Eh?
咦咦咦
I'm going to chop wood.
我要去劈柴了
I need to prepare for club activities.
我要準備社團活動了
I'm going to do laundry.
我去洗衣服
Ah, I'll help you.
啊 我來幫妳
I thought about that…
我想了想…
But don't we already get enough exercise in our daily lives?
我們平時的運動量 本來就已經很大了吧
Indeed.
的確是呢
Yeah.
的確是
Kagura, why don't you give it a try?
話說 神樂妳不運動嗎
I'm already an adult.
我已經是成年人了
And I'm quite happy with my physique.
而且我身材也保持的不錯
-As expected of an adult… -So cunning.
-真不愧是成年人… -真狡猾
Is there… only one solution left?
果然還是…只有那一個方法了嗎
We have to diet.
我們只能節食了
Ugh!
呃啊
DIET
(節食)
Wait a second!
先等一下啦
But there's no other way!
但是沒有別的方法了啊
I know that.
這我知道
But a diet would require cooperation from Akagami, right?
但是節食的話 不是需要赤神的協助嗎
That's correct…
妳說得沒錯…
It's a temple rule.
寺廟的規矩
We can't waste the food we make.
做出的飯不能浪費
Given this rule,
只要有這條規矩
we can only ask Akagami
我們就只能讓赤神做得
to make less food than usual.
比平時少一些了
But I feel a bit… embarrassed…
但是 如果讓赤神知道我們在減肥
to let Akagami know that I'm trying to lose weight.
會讓我覺得有點…不好意思…
-Tsukuyo is so cute. -Eh?
-月夜好可愛 -咦
-Tsukuyo is so young girl-like.
-月夜姐好少女
Tsukuyo is so lewd.
月夜姐姐又色又可愛
Kurage?
海月
How about getting married straight away?
妳乾脆跟他結婚不就好了
Marriage!
結婚
What are you talking about, Kagura?
妳在說什麼呀 神樂
I was thinking the same thing.
我也是這麼想的
I've come to see Akagami
我已經把赤神哥哥
as a very important family member.
當成了非常重要的家人了
If possible, I hope he can stay here forever.
可以的話 我希望他能一直在這裡待下去
Kurage…
海月…
If Tsukuyo were to marry him,
如果…月夜姐姐和他結婚的話
he could stay here forever, right?
他是不是就能一直待下去了呢…
Do you like Akagami that much?
原來妳這麼喜歡赤神嗎
Akagami's cooking is too good.
赤神哥哥做的飯太好吃
He has control over my stomach.
我的胃已經被他掌控了
I'm even willing to give up my sister for it.
就算要我把姐姐交出去也沒關係
What are you talking about, young lady?
妳這孩子也講得太誇張了吧
Do you compare your family to food?
家人和飯菜是可以相提並論的嗎
I'm about to cry!
姐姐我都要哭了哦
Family isn't food.
家人可不是食物哦
Hasn't any nutrition gone into your brain?
營養沒往妳大腦裡跑嗎
Since Sis Yuzuki is already engaged,
因為結月姐姐已經有婚約了
how about you marry Akagami?
所以月夜姐姐就和赤神哥哥結婚吧
Isn't that a bit too casual?
我的婚姻是不是有點太隨意了
If that's the case, why don't you marry Akagami, Kurage?
如果妳要這麼說的話 那海月妳去和赤神結婚不就好了
Just kidding.
我開玩笑的
I'm going to seduce Akagami.
我這就去色誘赤神哥哥
LET'S ESTABLISH FACTS! Wait!
(Let's既定事實！) 給我等等
Upon reflection,
仔細想想
the dishes Akagami makes
赤神做的料理
are generally fine and low-calorie.
基本上都是低熱量的素齋
Is it because we are still growing?
所以這是不是因為我們 都進入了成長期的的關係呢
Yes, that's right!
嗯嗯 成長期
We're all still growing!
我們都還在成長呢
I see.
原來如此
So this must be
所以這肯定是所謂的
a normal weight.
正常體重
And the weight will definitely
而且我們的體重肯定也會
bounce back quickly.
迅速恢復原樣的
My apologies for the wait.
大家久等了
Today, I've attempted to make Japanese sweets.
今天我試著挑戰了一下日式點心
Take your time and enjoy.
大家慢慢品嚐吧
Akagami, you…
赤神 你這傢伙
A-Akagami…
赤 赤神
Marriage.
結婚
Oh my…
哎呀呀
MALFUNCTION It's so delicious!
(已故障) 好好吃
Today,
今天
the dishes and sweets Akagami made are as delicious as always…
赤神哥哥做的飯菜和點心 也一如既往的美味…
I still hope he can stay here forever.
我果然還是希望 赤神哥哥能一直待在這裡呢
Can he wait for me
他能不能等到我
until I grow up?
長大的那一天呀
(TenPuru -No one can live on loneliness-) A DROP IN THE BUCKET
(妙廟美少女) (杯水車薪)
Akagami.
赤神
Yuzuki, what's wrong?
結月 妳怎麼了
Hmm…from now on,
嗯…從今往後
could you please add a portion of pickled radish to each meal?
能請你每餐都幫我們加一份醃蘿蔔嗎
That's no problem…
這倒是沒問題…
Thank you, Akagami!
謝謝你 赤神
I'll leave it to you then.
那就拜託你啦
But why pickled radish?
但為什麼是醃蘿蔔
An axe? Why is she carrying an axe?
斧頭 她為什麼要扛著斧頭
She's not going to execute me, right?
不會是要對我行刑吧…
No way… Yuzuki wouldn't do something like that…
不會吧…結月是不會做出這種…
That sound… I can't be mistaken…
那聲音…不會有錯的
She's practicing beheading!
她在練習斬首
Splitting the whole head in half?
是要把我的整個腦袋劈成兩半嗎
Akagami…
赤 神
I must do something to please her.
我 我必須做點什麼討她開心才行
Wow, what a luxurious breakfast!
哇 好豪華的早餐
It looks delicious.
看起來好好吃啊
I'm flattered.
各位過獎了
I've put my heart into this meal. These are all Yuzuki's favorite food.
這些可是我的得意之作 全都是結月愛吃的東西
This should be able to dispel her displeasure.
這樣應該就能驅散她的不愉快了
NO REACTION She has no reaction?
(毫無反應) 她居然毫無反應
Akagami, what's wrong?
赤神 你怎麼了
No, it's not over yet.
不 還沒完
This is the top-grade pickled radish she ordered.
這是她點的極品醃蘿蔔
She will definitely be happy after eating this.
她吃了這個一定會高興的
CHEWING
(咀嚼咀嚼 咀嚼咀嚼)
My life… is over.
我的人生…結束了
Akagami, Akagami…
赤神 赤神
When is the execution day?
行刑日是哪一天呢
Can you give me one more chance before that?
在那之前能不能再給我一次機會
Yuzuki… what's wrong this time?
結月…這次又是怎麼了
Yuzuki…
結月…
I can't stand it anymore! My legs are numb!
不行了 我腿麻了
Akagami, you're just in time!
赤神你來得正好
Help! Give me a hand…
你 你扶我一下…
What about my execution?
那 我的行刑呢
What do you mean?
什麼意思
Anyway, give me a hand first.
總之 你先拉我一把
Who told you to stop on your own?
誰讓妳擅自中斷的
Punishment.
予以懲罰
-Don't, Kiki! -Take this!
-嬉嬉姐不要呀 -看招看招
Spare me.
饒了我吧
I really can't… anymore…
真的不行…我不行了…
Why does it feel
怎麼感覺
so erotic…
這場面好色…
What was that just now? Practicing?
修行嗎 妳說的是剛剛那個嗎
To be precise, it's training practice.
正確來說應該是修行的練習
You must get used to it first.
畢竟得先習慣一下嘛
Training?
練習嗎
That was prostration.
剛剛的那是跪拜
PROSTRATION
(跪拜)
PLEASE ACCEPT ME AS YOUR DISCIPLE. NO WAY!
(請收我為徒) (想都別想)
It's only the first level of the Head Temple's training,
雖然只是總寺院修行的第一關
but you couldn't stand it after only two hours…
但是妳才兩個小時就成這樣了…
In reality, you have to keep it for two whole days.
實際可是要跪上整整兩天呢
So the thing this morning was also…?
難不成今天早上的那個也是嗎
That was wood-chopping training.
那是在練習劈柴
You'll have to do it every day at the training site in the future.
畢竟以後到修行場所每天都要劈嘛
I thought I was really going to be dismembered.
我還以為自己真的要被肢解了
What were you thinking?
你怎麼會這麼想
And today's breakfast.
今天的早餐也是這樣
No talking at table.
吃飯時嚴禁說話
CHEWING And no noises.
(咀嚼咀嚼) 而且不允許發出任何聲音
Even while chewing pickled radish!
就算吃的是醃蘿蔔也是
So that was training as well.
原來那也是修行啊
In short, this child is really useless.
總之 這孩子實在是太笨拙了
In order to become an abbot as soon as possible,
為了讓她能盡快成為住持
you can't do without a lot of practice.
她必須多練習一下才行呢
-Indeed. -Indeed?
-有道理 -哪裡有了
Anyway, that's how it is.
反正就是這麼一回事了
It might cause you a lot of trouble.
可能會給你添不少麻煩
-But I still need your help. -No problem.
-但你還是多多協助她吧 -沒問題
Training, huh… it's truly befitting of Yuzuki.
修行啊…不愧是結月
I too wish to tread the path of enlightenment soon.
我也想早日走上開悟之路啊
No! The most pressing matter right now is to fully support Yuzuki.
不 現在最重要的就是全力支援結月
Ah, right.
啊 對了
Why don't you try training as well?
你要不要也試試修行呢
Can I?
我可以嗎
You seem to be eager.
因為 你看起來一臉渴望 如果不讓你修行
If I don't let you train, I'm afraid you might attack Yuzuki on the spot.
我怕你會因為 欲求不滿而當場襲擊結月
Do I look that way? I'm sorry!
原來我露出那種表情了嗎 對不起
But,
不過
am I entitled to training?
我有修行的資格嗎
I'm still in debt.
我還欠著錢呢
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼啊
Your every word and action in the temple,
你在寺廟裡的一言一行
I've been watching them closely.
我可是都看在眼裡呢
Be confident.
挺起胸膛吧
Your days here were not spent in vain.
你在這裡的日子可不是白過的
With you together, I'm more confident.
兩個人一起的話 我也就比較放心了
Please be tolerant of me.
請多多指教
And you too, Yuzuki.
妳也是 請妳多多指教
-Let's do our best together, Akagami. -Yes, let's do it.
-我們一起加油吧 赤神 -嗯 我們一起加油
Well…
那那那 那個
Miss Mia?
米亞小姐
Can I join the training too?
可不可以讓我也參加修行呢
Keep going!
加油加油
What?
咦
You also want to train?
米亞小姐 妳也要一起修行嗎
That's really reassuring.
那可真是令人安心
Really?
真的嗎
-Yes, we warmly welcome you! -I'm so happy!
-是的 我非常歡迎妳 -我好高興
So that's it. Please be tolerant of me!
事情就是這樣 還請多多指教
There's nothing to be afraid of anymore.
已經沒有什麼好怕的了
I'm back.
我回來啦
You've started training?
你們開始修行了嗎
With Sis Yuzuki?
而且還是和結月姐一起嗎
So, you're Kiki's disciples now?
你們拜嬉嬉姐為師了呀
-Exactly! -That's right!
-沒錯 -就是這樣
So, that means…
是嗎 也就是說…
You all are going to be ordained. It's not easy.
你們都要得度囉 真不容易
Ordained?
得度…
I forgot to explain to you.
我忘了給你們解釋了
Master…
師父…
There are many steps to becoming an abbot.
成為住持也是分階段的
Before entering the training site,
進入修行場所之前
you must be ordained first.
必須要先得度
The so-called ordination,
所謂得度
READING SCRIPTURES AND SUCH is learning the scriptures and rituals with the master,
(讀讀經文什麼的) 就是跟著師父學習經文和法事
FOLDING THE ROBE, WORK PROCESS and becoming a recognized monk.
(疊袈裟的方法 工作流程) 爭取成為被認可的僧侶
Simply put,
簡單來說
-it's equivalent to becoming a monk. -I see.
-就是等於出家 -原來如此
Eh? Am I not already a monk?
咦 難道我現在還不算 已經出家了嗎
You're just living in a temple.
你只是住在寺廟里而已
Living… in a temple… that's it?
我只是住在…寺廟裡…而已…
Akagami, what's wrong?
赤神 你怎麼了
The reason I can keep my sanity even living under the same roof with women
我之所以跟女性居住在同一個屋簷下 都還能保持理智
is because I thought I had become a monk.
就是因為我以為我已經出家了啊
HAREM!
(後宮！)
A pool of wine and bodies!
酒池肉林
Now I realize all of this is false,
然而當我現在發現 那些都是假象的時候
and my desires…
雜念就…雜念就…
Calm down, Akagami!
冷靜冷靜 赤神
That's right, you need to be calm.
沒錯 你得冷靜才行
HOLD TIGHTLY Then you shouldn't do this to him!
(抱緊) 那妳就別對他做這種事啊
This is also to exercise your resistance to desires.
我這也是在鍛煉他對抗雜念
Leave that kind of thing to me!
那種事情讓我來就好了
Ah, no…
啊 不是…
Is my path to enlightenment
我 我的開悟之路
all an illusion?
原來都是幻影嗎
That's not the case.
沒有這回事哦
The path to enlightenment
走向開悟的道路
is the path of enlightenment.
即為開悟之路
This is the second insight I had
這是我第一次開悟時
when I first achieved enlightenment, Akagami.
所發現的第二個心得哦 赤神
Yuzuki.
結月
Sis Kiki, my prostration has reached six hours!
嬉嬉姐 我的跪拜達到了六小時了哦
Is that so? Let me see.
是嗎 我看看
Seems unexpectedly easy.
意外地很輕鬆呢
You can proceed to the next training…
這樣就可以進行下一項…
Let me press here.
看招看招
You're still far behind.
妳還差得遠呢
You guys, go chop wood next.
你們幾個 接下來去劈柴吧
Huga!
呼嘎
Please be tolerant of my mistakes!
請多多指教
As expected of Yuzuki…
不愧是結月…
She's far ahead of me.
比我領先很多
Do you really think so?
你真的這麼想嗎
Yuzuki hasn't been ordained either.
結月也還沒有得度哦
In other words, just like you,
也就是說她和你們一樣
she hasn't become a monk.
都還沒有出家
Although she just talked big,
雖然她剛剛說得 好像一副很了不起的樣子
the only difference between her and you
但要說她和你們有什麼不同的話
should be the mind.
應該就是內心了
She could have been ordained after studying for a year with me,
本來 在我這裡的話 她必須得學習一年才能得度
but Yuzuki completed everything in just half a year.
但她打算只花半年就學完一切
And she hasn't missed any studies.
而且還是在兼顧學業的情況下
All of this is to become an abbot as soon as possible.
這都是她為了能盡早當上住持 所付出的努力
Because she doesn't want Mikazuki Temple to be abandoned.
那是因為 結月不希望三日月寺被廢寺
I can't dawdle any longer.
現在不是我拖拖拉拉的時候了
Yuzuki!
結月
Let me make my contribution!
請讓我也來出一份力吧
Sounds great.
就等你這句話了
Yuzuki.
結月
You said you'd fight alongside me.
你明明說要和我一起戰鬥的…
Eh, I never intended to abandon you…
呃 我並不是打算拋下妳…
Mia will also be with us, right?
米亞當然也會和我們一起練習 對吧
Let's master wood chopping together and get ordained.
我們一起掌握劈柴的技巧 一起得度吧
Chopping wood has nothing to do with ordination.
劈柴和得度可沒什麼關係呢
Who cares?
算了 隨便啦
Sis Kiki, Sis Yuzuki,
嬉嬉姐 結月姐姐
there's a guest.
有客人來了
Excuse us.
我來打擾了
Er…
呃
Mr. Houan?
峯安先生
He is Yuzuki's fiancé?
他就是結月姐的未婚夫嗎
What does he want?
他有什麼事呢
I have no idea.
我也完全不知道
Isn't he here to be lewd with Sis Yuzuki?
他不是來找結月姐姐色色的嗎
Kurage?
海月
After all, he's her fiancé.
畢竟是未婚夫嘛
It's an adult relationship.
是成人之間的關係
Oh dear.
哎呀呀
Yuzuki wouldn't be that kind of person!
結月姐不可能是那種人吧
Right, Akagami?
對吧 赤神
This man
這個男人
is going to use his status as her fiancé to…
要利用未婚夫的身份和結月…
Is that really the case?
真的是這樣嗎
This is special training.
看來這是特別修行呢
Mainly for the lower body.
主要是下半身的
What! I'm very interested!
妳說的是什麼 我好感興趣
I'm worried about Sis Yuzuki, so I plan to hide and watch till the end.
因為太擔心結月姐姐了 我們就躲起來在旁邊看到最後吧
Let's do that.
我們就這樣做吧
Why do you all seem to enjoy this?
為什麼你們看起來都好像樂在其中啊
Are you all Miss Yuzuki's family?
各位就是結月小姐的家人吧
I apologize for the sudden visit,
很抱歉我不請自來
but I really wanted to
但是我實在是很想
see with my own eyes the temple and family that she proudly spoke of.
親眼看看結月口中 自豪的寺廟和家人們
Er… well…
呃…不是…嗯
And there's a bit of trivial matter.
然後我也有點瑣事要辦
You're Mr. Akagami, right?
你是赤神先生 對吧
Could I have a word with you?
你可以來一下嗎
This is really…
這可真是…
much more serious than I imagined.
比我想像的要嚴重多了
I'm sorry.
讓您見笑了
Humph, if you're not satisfied, just go back.
哼 不滿意的話你就回去啊
Sis Kiki, why did you change your clothes?
嬉嬉姐妳怎麼也換衣服了呀
So, why was I called over?
為什麼我也被叫來了這裡
You haven't changed a bit, Kiki.
妳還是沒怎麼變呢 嬉嬉
Miss Aoba Yuzuki,
蒼葉結月小姐
you haven't been ordained yet, right?
妳好像還沒有得度 對吧
Um…
是的
So what, you jerk?
那又怎麼樣混蛋
Are you looking for trouble?
你想找麻煩嗎
What's wrong with Sis Kiki?
嬉嬉姐這是怎麼了
You know what? I'm now her master.
我就說出來嚇死你吧 現在我已經是這孩子的師父了
With my guidance,
有了我的指導
she can be ordained in half a year.
她半年就能得度
Wait, Kiki?
等等 嬉嬉姐
That's still too late.
那還是太遲了
Could you get ordained in three months?
可以請妳在三個月之內得度嗎
What nonsense are you talking about?
你在說什麼鬼話
You should also know about
本寺得度的難處
the difficulty of ordination in this temple…
你應該也有所…
If you can't do it…
如果妳做不到的話…
Please allow me to cancel the engagement.
就請容許我作廢婚約了
What color does Sis Tsukuyo like?
月夜姐姐 妳喜歡什麼顏色
Pink and sky blue, I guess.
粉色和天藍色吧
She also likes red, a passionate color.
不過我也喜歡紅色 是個熱情的顏色
Quite bold.
相當大膽呢
By the way, what color is it today?
順便問一下 妳今天是什麼顏色的
Wait a minute. What are you talking about?
等一下 妳說的是什麼
(Next Episode: What Color Are Your Panties?)
(下一話 內褲是什麼顏色的？)